真不敢相信
I can't believe it
就在这里
it's here
是时候了
it's time
嘿，你们好，我是TheCherno，欢迎来到这期预告视频
hey, what's up guys, my name is TheCherno, welcome to this announcement video
因为我们即将开始学习游戏引擎系列
because we are about to begin the game engine series
是的，你们没有听错，我真不敢相信已经多久了
yes, you heard me right, I can't believe how long it's been
我很高兴能这么说，但就是那样，游戏引擎系列已经准备好了
I'm so excited to say this, but that's it, the game engine series is ready
它马上就要出来了，下周就开始
and it's about to start coming out, starting next week
就这样，下次见
that's it, I'll see you guys next time
不，我在开玩笑，但说真的，我好像也不知道，大概已经计划了两年
no, I'm kidding, but seriously, it's like I don't know, I've been planning this for like the last two years probably
并且我已经有一个庞大的计划，一切都准备好了
and I've got this massive plan, everything's ready to go
我已经迫不及待想开始搞这个了，这对整个社区来说都是件大事
I've just, I can't wait to get started on this, it's gonna be a huge thing for the whole community
它不仅仅是我的工作，同时也是每个人的工作
it's not gonna be just me kind of working on, this is gonna be everyone
它会非常深入，非常详细，所有的视频中都会有大量的东西，它就是
it's gonna be really like in depth really detailed, there's gonna be heaps of just stuff, that's gonna go into all of the videos, it's just
我们要一起构建一些非常棒的东西，我太激动了，迫不及待地想开始这件事
we're gonna build something really really amazing together, and I'm so excited, and I just can't wait to actually start this thing
所以我现在很开心，我甚至都不知道
so I'm like, I'm just so happy right now, I can't even like
我不知道还能说什么，在这个视频中，只是想简单介绍一下游戏引擎系列到底是什么
I don't know what else to say, I'm gonna be, in this video, I'm just gonna go over a little bit about what on earth the game engine series is
对于你们这些已经知道的，对于那些可能才关注我频道的新人们
for those of you who are known, for those of you who might be new to my channel um
但那是我唯一真正为这个系列做的计划
but that's kind of my only plan really for this series
很明显，就是那样，就好像它来了，它准备好了，它会随时上线，就像，哦，我等不及了
and obviously just to say that, that's it, like it's coming, it's ready, it's gonna go up, like any time, it's just like, oh, I just can't wait
所以对于那些刚关注我频道的朋友来说，你们可能没有注意到这一点
so for those of you kind of new to my channel, you might not have noticed that
我有点喜欢这个频道，有点像一个编程频道，但它不仅限于像编程或游戏编程之类的东西
I kind of like this channel is kind of like a programming channel, but it's not just limited to like programming or game programming or anything like that
本质上，它只是一个围绕着我和我的兴趣的频道
essentially it's really just a channel that revolves around me and my interests
因为我喜欢教学，喜欢和大家分享我学到的一切，那一直是我的一个爱好
because I love teaching, and I love sharing everything that I learn with everyone, that's always been a passion of mine
对我来说，比如教我不感兴趣的东西，或者目前生活中没有做的，那是没有任何意义的
and it doesn't make any sense for me to like teach things that I'm not interested in or things that I'm not currently doing with my life
我现在在，近四年来，我一直是EA的游戏引擎开发者
I am, at the moment, and for the last almost four years now, I've been a game engine developer at EA
目前在Frostbite组织的移动引擎部门工作
currently working in the Frostbite organization on the mobile engine
所以，那就是我的生活，那就是我所做的，对吧，所以我喜欢和大家分享那个
so that's my life, that's what I do, right, so I love sharing that with everyone
并且说实话，就像教学一直是我的一大爱好
and to be honest, like just teaching has just always been a huge passion of mine
所以这个频道是什么样的，它实际上只是我在讨论我的爱好
so what this channel like, it really is is just me kind of talking about my passions
讨论我感兴趣的东西，无论是什么样的日志或教程视频
talking about stuff that interests me, whether that be kind of invlogs or tutorial videos
教你们我已经掌握的那些东西，或者只是我学到的新东西或者想到的东西
and teaching you guys kind of the same thing that I've learned, or just new things that I've picked up or things that I'm realizing
就像你们知道的，因为我感觉搞游戏引擎开发或游戏开发
because I feel that programming, and like you know, game engine development or game development
总的来说，就像，就像
is like, in general, has just been like, such a, like it's just been
太复杂了
it's been over complicated so so so much
就像在很多情况下一样，我喜欢我的教学方式，因为我也做私人课程
and I feel like with the way that I teach, like in a lot of cases, because I do private sessions as well
非常有限，说真的，因为我很忙，但我确实有大约五个学生，我会一对一地私下教他们
very limited, like seriously, because like I'm so busy, but I do have like five or so students who I do teach privately one on one
就像我解释一些东西的时候，他们对一切都有种豁然开朗的感觉
just the way that everything clicks for them when I explain something
因为我试着把它简单化，然后实际上，你们知道的，如果仔细想想，其实没那么难
because I try and kind of simplify it, and just be like well actually, you know if you think about it, you know it's not actually that difficult
就像我很喜欢那样，我想那反映了我的频道是关于什么的
like I just love doing that so much, and that's kind of a reflection of what my channel I guess is about
这是关于我教我的爱好和感兴趣的东西，有一点预感，就像用一种简单的方式
it's about kind of me teaching my passions and what the stuff that I'm interested in, in a bit of a scent, like in a simple way and kind of hopefully
在这种情况下，我会帮助你们很多人，因为那就是我喜欢做的
in that case helping a lot of you people out, because that's what I love to do
现在我想说的是，我的爱好，根本不在于游戏编程
now what I want to say is that my passions, don't lie in game programming at all
就像我不喜欢游戏一样，我几乎可以那么说，就那么简单
like I don't like games, I almost I'll say that, like it's as simple as that
我不在业余时间玩游戏，我年轻的时候，我想我还是个孩子的时候，玩过一些
I don't I don't play games in my spare time, I did kind of, when I was younger, when I was like a kid, I guess
但基本上成年后，就像你们知道的，除了偶尔和朋友一起玩多人游戏
but like basically as soon as I became an adult apart from the occasional like you know, in a game of something multiplayer with friends
在业余时间根本不玩游戏，我只是对那个不感兴趣，也不是说
like I don't play games in my spare time at all, I'm just not interested in that, I'm not saying that
比如我反对那样或者像游戏或者邪恶或者游戏是坏的，就像这是浪费时间一样
like I'm against that or like games or evil or games are bad, like it's a waste of time
就我个人而言，我觉得很无聊，好像这不是我真正喜欢做的事情
just for me personally I get bored, like it's just not something I enjoy doing really
当然，制作游戏也是我不喜欢做的事情
so of course making games is also something that I don't necessarily enjoy doing
我真正感兴趣和喜欢的是制作游戏引擎
what I am really interested in and what I do enjoy a lot is making game engines
最近在德国制作了一段log的视频，我将把链接放在那里，这是关于
and I actually made a video of log in Germany recently, which I will link up there which is about
你们知道的，游戏vs引擎，决定你们想做什么，只是在讨论差异，外面太亮了
you know, games vs engines, and kind of deciding what it is that you want to make, and kind of just talking about the differences, it's so bright out here
只是说说它们之间的区别，你们知道的，制作游戏和制作引擎的感觉之类的
and just talking about the differences kind of between you know, what it's like to make a game vs what it's like to make an engine and all of that
那么就去看看那个视频，如果你们想和我见面，进一步了解我在这里谈论的内容
so check out that video, if you want kind of to meet me to expand a little bit more about what I'm talking about here
因为那不是这期视频的主题，但重点是
because that's not what this video is about, but the point is
就像我真的不喜欢游戏，我真的喜欢做游戏，但真正喜欢的是开发引擎
like I don't really like games, I really like making games, but what I do love doing is making engines
我猜这就是这个频道的内容，就像你们知道的，我在过去两年中一直在教的OpenGL中的C++
and I guess this is kind of what this channel is about and like you know the C++ in the OpenGL stuff that I've been teaching over the last almost two years
已经有点特别针对，对吧，让我们把所有那些都拿出来，现在让我们实际开发一个引擎
now has kind of been specifically geared towards, right, let's take all that and let's actually build an engine now
就像我要说的，我要把这个命名为游戏引擎系列，对吧
and again like I am gonna say, I am titling this the game engine series, right
但它不一定会成为游戏引擎，我的意思是，如果你们想想游戏引擎是什么
but it's not really necessarily going to be a game engine, I mean if you think about what a game engine is
并且我特别想做的是，它就像一个3D实时渲染应用程序
and what specifically I want to be building is, it's just really like kind of a 3D real time rendering application
就是这样，对吧，这是一种方法，也就是一个制作3D实时渲染应用程序的引擎，对吧
that's what it is, right, it's a way, it's an engine to make a 3D real time rendering application, right
我希望能够做到的，以及互动式的，我想做的就是让这个框架成为这个引擎
what I want to be able to do, and an interactive one at that as well, what I want to be able to do is make kind of this framework this engine
这样人们就可以构建实时交互的3D应用程序，那就是我的想法，对吧，使用3D显卡
so that people can construct real time interactive 3D applications, that is the idea, right, with 3D graphics, that's the idea
所以你们当然可以把它应用到游戏中，当然我的意思是很多人会这么做
so of course you could apply that to games, absolutely I mean a lot of people will
那将是非常好的优化，为了满足，比如你们知道的
it's going to be very well optimized for kind of, you know
大场景和很多实体，以及诸如此类的东西
big scenes and lots of entities, and all of that kind of stuff
我可能会加入脚本和所有与游戏相关的代码，因为那也不一定只适用于游戏，对吧
and I'll probably throw in scripting and all of that kind of gameplay related code, because that's not necessarily applicable to just games either right
我们将要开发的这个引擎，它的功能远远不止制作游戏
what we're gonna be building is this engine, that's capable of so much more than just making games
它只是能够呈现交互式3D图形，那真的很酷
it's just capable of rendering interactive 3D graphics like, that's really cool
所以我迫不及待地想和大家一起构建它，我会简单地谈谈它将包括什么
so I can't wait to kind of build that with everyone, I'll talk a little bit about what it's going to include
我们不会有一个概述视频来讨论整个项目的各个阶段
I'm not like we'll have an overview video where we discus kind of the stages of this whole project
我可能会喜欢在白板上，而不是真的在白板上，就像平板电脑一样，这样你们就能看到
and I'll probably like right kind of on a whiteboard, not really on a whiteboard, like a tablet, so that you guys can see
我们会一步一步来，我现在不想那么做，如果只是一时兴起的话，肯定就会错过一些东西
and we'll kind of go through everything step by step，I don't want to really do that now, just off the top of my head, because I'm sure I'll miss things
我不想现在就掏出笔记，我们需要坐在办公室的工作室里
and I don't want to pull up notes now, we want to kind of sit down in the studio in the office
如果你们愿意的话，可以先把它过一遍，但话虽如此
if you will, and actually go through that, but that being said
你们知道的，我们会把这个项目分解成一步一步来搞
you know we are gonna kind of break down the project and go through everything step by step
但我的想法是，我们要一起构建这个东西，现在，让我来计划这个系列
but the idea is like we're gonna kind of build this thing together, now, over me planning this series
我花了这么长时间的原因之一是，这是一个非常复杂的任务
and one of the reasons why I took so long was because it's just such a massively complicated task
开发一个这样的引擎需要整个团队的人花费数年时间，对吧
building an engine like this takes years for a whole team of people, right
现在我很幸运，因为我多少知道自己在做什么
now I'm fortunate in the fact that I kind of more or less know what I'm doing
因为我确实有多年制作游戏引擎的经验
because I do have so many years of experience of actually making kind of a game engine
在游戏引擎团队中，所以我知道如何制作游戏引擎
and being in a game engine team, so I do know how to make a game engine
我从来没有真正坐下来，从零开始做一个完整的引擎
I've never really sat down, and made a full kind of engine from scratch
我会把它考虑到，就这样，我们现在可以用这个引擎来发布应用程序了吗
where I would consider it to the point of like, that's it, we can ship applications with this engine now
因为它从来没有完全功能正确，我从来没有真正做过
because it has ever fully featured right, I've never actually done that in my life
我知道每件事是如何工作的，我已经在不同的模块中分别做了
I know how everything works, and I've done it all separately in different modules
而是把它们整合成一个大项目，这不是我真正做过的事情，对吧
but to combine it all into one huge project, not something that I've really done, right
并且那是我一直想做的事情，所以这并不一定是我想做的
and that's something that I've just been wanting to do, so this isn't, even just necessarily me being like all right
让我们做一个关于如何制作游戏引擎的系列，这就是我想做的，我现在就想做一个游戏引擎
let's make a series on how to make a game engine, this is me being like, that's it, I want to make a game engine now
我想做我自己的引擎，我想让大家从头开始做我们自己的引擎
I want to make my own engine, I want us to make our own engine right from the ground up
但不像sparky，那是我三年前做的另一个引擎，我想是三年半前
but unlike sparky which was another engine that I did make about three years ago, three and a half years ago I think now
对吧，差不多就是这样的，比如你们知道的
right, yeah that was kind of more or less, you know
特别是对于游戏来说，那是一种快速组合，因为它之前确实是那样的
for games specifically and that was very kind of like quickly put together, because it was
我花了40天的时间制作了一个基础版本，是为了一个游戏编程比赛
I made it in like the base, the base version of it in like 40 days for for a game programming competition
但这就像，就像正因为如此，我就像这样，撸码，然后解释一些东西，鉴于这只是一个教程
but like this is gonna be, like and because of that it was kind of me, typing code and then explaining something along the way, whereas this is gonna be a tutorial
就像这需要时间，慢慢来，对我来说，一切都是新鲜的
like this is gonna take time, it's gonna be like slow, it's gonna be, it's gonna fish in me
比如写东西，给你们画图表，做笔记等等
like writing stuff, drawing diagrams for you guys, notes all of that kind of stuff
这几乎是一个完整的目标，对吧，它不会只是我刚刚做的事情
it's gonna be like a full cause almost, right, it's not going to be just something that I just
你们知道的，即兴发挥，这是计划好的
you know, whip up and kind of improvise on, it's been planned
就像这整件事，我要解释所有的事情
it's like this whole thing, where I'm actually going to explain everything
正因为如此，这些视频会很长，实际上不会很长
and because of that these videos are going to be long, not actually long
但是会非常详细，我们可能不会马上得到很多
but there's going to be very detailed, and we might not get very far immediately
好像要花很长时间才能构建好
like it's going to take a lot of time to actually build this up
基本上就像这个引擎，我确信，很明显，很明显，我的生活
and basically it's almost like this engine, and I'm sure that obviously obviously my life
就像随着技术的不断进步，我可能会放弃这个，最终创造一个新的引擎
like I will probably scrap this eventually make a new engine as technology continues to improve
随着我变得更聪明，我也会学习新东西，显然我们都在学习新东西，对吧
and as I get smarter and I'd learn new things as well, obviously we're all learning new things, right
但这对我来说就像是一个小小的生活计划
but this is almost like just a almost like a little life project for me
这是我一生中想要做的事情，我想要创造一个游戏引擎
it's just something that I want to do in my life, I want to build a game engine
你们要关注我，并且我也会和你们一起练习，解释一切
you guys gonna watch me, and I'm also going to work on it with you guys, and I'm also going to explain everything
教你们，我在做什么，怎么做，我们要一起做决定
and teach you, what I'm doing, how I'm doing, and we're going to decide things together, and we're going to decide things together
所以这将是一个非常令人兴奋的项目，我等不及要开始了
so it's going to be a really exciting project, and I absolutely can't wait to get this thing started
这是我一生都想做的事，基本上是我在YouTube上的所有韩国生活
it's been just, I've been wanting to do this my whole life, basically all of my whole kind of YouTube korea life
终于要开始了，我太激动了，现在你们要加入了
and it's finally happening, and I'm so excited, now you guys are gonna come in
事实上，我将积极与你们合作，这将是github上的一个公共项目
in the fact that like I am going to actively work with you guys, this is gonna be a public project on github
它将是完全免费的，当然，它只会出现在Github上
it's gonna be completely free, of course it's just gonna be like up on Github
你们可以查看每一个提交，可以记录问题，他们会像问题跟踪会像一个项目
you can look through every commit,  you can log issues, they'll be like issue tracking will have like a project
因为它就像一个预告栏，你们可以在Github上看，现在是Github项目
because it's like almost like a trailer board you could have on github, now github project or whatever's called
我们会像专业游戏那样，把所有东西都准备好，我想人们会过来的
we're going to have that full thing set up, like a professional games you do, well I think people are coming
无论如何，专业的游戏，你们是一支专业的团队，它会非常非常酷，完全免费
anyway, professional games, you're a professional team, and it's gonna be so so so cool, that's gonna be completely free
所以你们会与仓库进行交互甚至可能得到合作者的帮助
so you guys are gonna interact with that repository potentially even get collaborators in to help
对吧，关于这个代码，因为这将是一件非常大的事情，因为这是一个非常大的项目
right, the code for this, because again it is gonna be such a big thing, and because it's such a big project
那确实需要大量的时间和大量的工作，很明显，我将不得不在某些地方一笔带过
that does kind of require a lot of man hours a lot of work, obviously I'm going to have to cock corners in some places
我不能一边解释这些东西，一边用视频记录下来，一边独自建立Unity或Unreal
I can't just build like Unity or Unreal by myself, while explaining all of it and documenting it on video
那在实际上是不可能的，我也不想现实一点
that's physically impossible, and I'm not trying to be realistic and be like
那就是我要做的，它不像，比如，带有关卡编辑器和游戏引擎工具的
that's what I'm gonna do, it's not like, for example, with the level editor and game engine tools
就是那样，都将被内置到实际的游戏运行时中，就像使用ImGui一样
that's all, gonna be kind of built into the actual game runtime, like using ImGui
因为这不是我能随随便便就能做到的
because it's not something that I can just be like
再说一次，那样的话，我将创造一个完整的窗口应用，即带有我自己的UI框架的关卡编辑器
again, I'm going to make a full windows application, that's going to be a level editor with my own UI framework
那是不可能的，绝不可能，对吧，这种东西太费时间了
with, that's not going to happen, it's impossible, right, like this stuff takes so much time
所以我不得不做出一些妥协，以使这个项目切实可行，我想了很多
so there have been compromises that I've had to make in order to actually make this project realistic, and I have thought about a lot of them
是的，我的意思是，但它仍然会很棒，我真的等不及了
and yeah I mean like it's, but it's still gonna be amazing, and I absolutely can't wait
我们会从头开始使用很多东西，当然就会使用库
and we are gonna be riding a lot of things from scratch, we'll be using libraries obviously
所有3D库的开发工具，比如代码框架之类的东西，那是会发生的
and all the kind of 3D party vendor comes to blood tools and like code frameworks or whatever, that's gonna happen
希望风，不会吧，阿西吧，但总的来说，很多内容都是从头开始写的
hopefully the wind, isn't, bad, but overall, a lot of it is gonna be written from scratch from the ground up
这将是非常非常非常令人兴奋的，如果你们想要支持这个项目的话
which is gonna be really really really exciting, now if you want to support this project
因为我确实需要你们的帮助，这要花很多时间，已经费了我不少时间了
because I do need your help, this is gonna take a lot of my time, it already has
所以如果你们想看到这个项目真正变得更生动，更多这样的内容会出现
so if you want to see this project actually kind of come to life and more of these episodes to go up
我真的需要你们的支持，所以我有一个patreon patreon.com/TheCherno
I really do need your support, so I do have a patreon patreon.com/TheCherno
当然你们的支持也会得到奖励
you will get rewards for helping to support of course
比如提早获得游戏引擎源代码，实际项目将在github上免费开源
such as early access to game engine source code, the actual project will be on github will be public will be free
但你们会在它实际运行之前得到代码，还会得到实验性开发分支
but you'll get kind of code before it actually goes up, you'll also get experimental development branches
就像我在制作视频之前已经实现了某些功能一样
which is like me already having implemented certain features before I make the video about them
并且那就可能要等几个月，对吧
like and that could be months before right
你们会看到我写代码，就像在做视频之前，我自己写代码一样之类的
so you'll kind of see me write the code, as I write the code myself before I make videos and all that stuff
你们也可以和我一起聚会，比如在discord上，每个月就会有一次视频聊天
and you can also hang out with me on like um on discord, we have like a video chat once a month
我们有各种各样的伙伴，比如有提供一行代码的伙伴
where we all have all the kind of partner, which is like there's a tier code partner
所有的伙伴都会在一起进行视频聊天，我们会讨论一些事情
all of the partners kind of will kind of hang out in a video chat and we talk about stuff
并且去年我们就一直在讨论游戏引擎系列
and we've been talking about the game engine series for the last year
所以那些人其实对我现在说的还是很了解的
so those guys actually know a lot about what I'm saying here now
这很酷，因为你们知道，我想大概有20个左右的伙伴，他们什么都知道
which is pretty cool, because you know that kind of like, I think that's 20 or so partners, they know like everything
真的很酷，当我们有了自己的只在discord上聊天之类的伙伴，那么你们会得到一些奖励
which is really cool, when we have like our own partner only discord chat and all of that, so you do get a handful of rewards
但最重要的是，你们让我工作时间少了些，而是把更多的时间用来开发这个游戏引擎系列
but most of all, you're just allowing me to kind of maybe work less, and kind of spend more of my time developing this game engine series
因为你们会在经济上支持我，所以那是一件很棒的事情
because you'll kind of be supporting me financially, so that's just such an amazing thing
并且我非常感谢那些让我花这么多时间在这个项目上的人
and I'm so grateful for the people who have made it realistic for me to actually spend so much of my time on this
所以一定要抓住这个机会，让我们看看我们能一起创造出多大的游戏引擎
so definitely jump on that, and let's see let's see how big of a game engine we can all built together
以及我们能做得多好，我都等不及了
and how good we can make it, I absolutely can't wait
下次见，爱你们哟，拜
I will see you guys next time, oh I love all of you, goodbye